NETWORK ADMINISTRATOR IV

Summary

Senior Systems Administrator with over 20 years of related IT experience. I have a wide-breadth of knowledge in Active Directory, Citrix and VMware. I work well in a team environment and I am self-sufficient, highly-motivated and someone you can rely on.

Highlights

Experience

Network Administrator IV

July 2010 to October 2015 Peraton - Dahlgren, VA

- Senior Administrator in a three member team overseeing support for 150+ VM's and 30+ physical servers in two major datacenters located in Fort Worth, Texas and Calgary, Canada and remote gas plants located throughout Texas, Colorado, Montana and Alberta, Canada.
- SME for VMware and Citrix.
- 150+ VM's (97% virtualized in US/80% in Canada) running vSphere 5.1, 41 U3 in US and 4.0 in Canada.
- ESX hardware primarily resides on Dell PowerEdge r900, r820, r810 and 2950's servers.

Senior Server Support Professional

April 2007 to July 2010 Cognizant Technology Solutions - Columbia, SC

- Lead Citrix Engineer for Textron account, including Bell Helicopter, Cessna, Textron Financial Systems, Kautex, EZGO.
- Performed successful migrations from Metaframe XP to Presentation Server 4.0, 4.5, PS 3.0 to PS 4.5 and PS 4.0 to XenApp 5.0 and 6.0, which included upgrading of the server hardware, setting up AD group policy objects for TS/Citrix, and establishing Application Installation and Security processes to ensure a tightly controlled environment.
- Support of Textron's VMware (VSphere 4.0) environment, including performing P2V migrations, analyzing existing physical servers for migration candidates and daily support of the environment.
- Performed Business Continuity server testing for Textron at their IBM DR/Continuity sites in Boulder, Colorado and Sterling Forest, NY for the Wintel Group.
- Support of Textron's global Citrix, Vmware and Wintel environment.
- Presentation Server 4.0/4.5/5.0 on W2K3.
- 300+ Wintel Servers including both physical IBM xSeries 3850, 3650, 336.
- Dell PowerEdge 6650 (ESX Hosts) and VMWare guests.
- Multiple Citrix Farms in multiple locations in U.S and selected global locations.
- We have a mixture of Access Gateway 4.6, Citrix Secure Gateway 3.0, Web Interface in the DMZ with various external user groups (Boeing, Edwards AFB, etc.) in support of the VH-22, ARH, Huey and multiple other military and commercial projects.
- Many proprietary and off the shelf applications hosted on Citrix and Vmware utilizing both SQL Server and Oracle database back ends.
- Operating Systems consists of Windows Server 2008, W2K3R2, W2K3 and W2K.
- Vmware hosted at multiple locations in U.S.
- Using Dell PowerEdge and IBM server hardware, running a mixture of VSphere 4.0 and ESX 3.5 with mainly Windows OS on the guest VM/s
- We are using Vmotion, DRS and HA attached to multiple SAN flavors including Hitachi and EMC Clariion.

Citrix Engineer

January 2007 to April 2007 Alcon Laboratories - City, STATE

- Support of Alcon's global Citrix environment: Presentation Server 4.0\W2K3, Metaframe XP FR3\W2K, Metaframe 1.8\TSE.
- 300+ Servers (Physical HP DL380G4's and Vmware Virtual Machines).
- 3 production Citrix farms 1 per each MF version, 3 Development farms 1 per each MF version.
- Citrix Secure Gateway, Nfuse 1.7.
- Mix of HP, Xerox and Canon printers.
- 60+ applications with a mixture of custom in-house apps coded with Powerbuilder and off the shelf software with many of the apps back ended to Documentum.

Senior IST Analyst

January 1999 to January 2006 Burlington Resources, Inc - City, STATE

- Network Team
- Part of a ten member enterprise infrastructure team responsible for all areas of Active Directory, Exchange mail services, File/Print services, Citrix, VMWare and the underlying operating systems and hardware for 3500 employees in locations worldwide.
- Windows Team Lead.
- Overseeing a team of five Administrators for the support and maintenance of the Window 2000/2003 Server operating system file and print
 services, Citrix Metaframe XP, Vmware ESX and overall support of the underlying hardware for the HP Proliant, Dell PowerEdge servers
 for the approximately 350 servers and 3500 clients located in major divisional and remote offices around the world.
- VMWare Project Core Team Member.
- One-half of project team responsible for architecting, planning, testing and implementing VMWare ESX Server 2.5.2 in BR's five major

- divisional locations in the U.S., U.K and Canada.
- Windows 2003/Exchange 2003 Project Core Team Member.
- Part of a three member team responsible for the upgrade from Windows 2000 to the Windows 2003 operating system and Exchange 2000 to Exchange 2003 across the enterprise.
- Citrix Metaframe Project Lead.
- Responsible for the upgrade of Citrix Metaframe 1.8 to Metaframe XP and the upgrade from Terminal Server 4.0 to Windows 2000.
- Windows 2000 Server/Banyan Project Core Team Member.
- Project involved the migration from Banyan Vines operating system to Active Directory/Windows 2000 Server, and the migration of BeyondMail to Exchange Server 2000.

NT Server Administrator

January 1989 to January 1999 TTI, Inc - City, STATE

- Project leader for the implementation of Citrix Metaframe 1.0/1.8 and Microsoft Windows Terminal Server 4.0 thin client solution.
- Responsible for all aspects of the thin client project, including planning, testing, installation and support for internal clients using Wyse Winterm 2315 terminals, and support for the dial in ICA clients located world-wide.
- Responsible for testing the bandwidth requirements of the Citrix ICA protocol for the planned rollout of 35 WAN linked branches for approximately 800 end users located throughout the United States.
- Installed, implemented and provided support for Microsoft Exchange Server 5.5.
- Responsible for support of 21 NT 4.0 servers including IBM Netfinity 7000's, Netfinity 5500, PC Server 325's and Compaq 2500's.
- Implemented a disaster recovery / new install solution using the HP SureWriter CDRW and Symantec's Ghost for both server and workstations.
- Project leader for Tivoli's Software Distribution, Remote Control and Inventory Management solutions.

Staff Sergeant, Medical Administrative Specialist

January 1985 to January 1993 U.S. Air Force - City, STATE

- 609th Contingency Hospital Group, Zweibrucken AB, Germany, Operation Desert Storm
- 301st Tactical Fighter Wing, Carswell AFB Medical Center, Carswell AFB, Texas.
- Keesler Medical Center, Keesler AFB, MS.

Education

B.S : Management , 1996 LeTourneau University - City , State Skills

Windows Server 2012 R2, Windows Server 2008 R2, Windows Server 2003, VMware ESXi 5.1, vCenter 5.1, Site Recovery Manager 5.1, Citrix XenApp 7.6, 6, Presentation Server 4.